There have been a ton of interesting
developments in the world of AI over the
past couple of weeks, and today I'm
going to get you all caught up. We've
got some impressive new video models,
smart glasses that seem to blow
everybody's mind, some big AI updates
out of YouTube, and a new app that'll
actually pay you to let AI spy on your
phone calls. All that and more in
today's AI news roundup. There's a lot
to cover, and I don't want to waste your
time, so let's dig right in.
Get in my belly. Starting with the
newest feature inside of ChatGpt. It's
called Chat GPT Pulse. And it's
basically a daily news digest that
ChatGpt will send to your phone every
morning based on what it knows about
you. Pulse proactively does research to
deliver personalized updates based on
your chats feedback and connected apps
like calendar. You can curate what
ChatGpt researches by letting it know
what's useful and what isn't. So, when I
open up the chat GPT phone on my app
here, we can see a new screen. I'm here
to surface what's helpful to you once a
day, every day. You decide what shows
up. If you tell me what to focus on,
I'll curate it for you tomorrow. And we
can see some of the stuff that it
curated for me. And I'm guessing this is
just based on previous conversations
I've had with chat GPT and what it knows
about me, like the AI toothbrush
gimmick. I definitely need to know more
about what that is. everyday objects
with attitude. Coffee makers that nag,
lamps that boast. Interesting. And then
we can see it says you decide what shows
up here. What's on your mind lately?
I'll remember it for tomorrow's updates.
So if I put I'm curious about and then
put the latest AI news updates.
Tomorrow's curation should have
information about that. This to me seems
very much like Perplexity's like
discover feature. Although this feels
even more tailored to you, where
Perplexity seems like it's a little bit
more general news. But this could come
in pretty handy. And if I'm being
honest, this is kind of scary for the
newsletter business, which if you know
me, I have a very large newsletter, the
Future Tools Newsletter, that curates
all the latest AI tools and news.
Something like this might just curate it
to your phone without you needing to
read emails. I hate to say it, but it's
kind of reality. We got access to a ton
of new video models this week as well,
including Luma's Ray 3, which is the
world's first reasoning video model.
They also claimed to be the first to
generate studiograde HDR or high dynamic
range video. There's also a new draft
mode where you can have it generate the
video pretty quickly, but in sort of a
lower resolution, lower quality, and
then if you like the way the draft
version came out, you can have it
generate it in a higher quality version.
It also apparently has much better
physics and seems pretty solid. I
actually got a demo in person in New
York a few days ago, but let's go ahead
and try it out. I'll jump over to
lumalabs.ai/dreamachine.
Once inside Dream Machine, let's click
the plus here. And then down in the
bottom, we should be able to change the
model. So, right now, we've got ray 2.
And I could select ray 3 or ray 3
reasoning. Let's go ahead and use the
reasoning model. And let's set the
dynamic range to HDR. It should give us
a sort of larger variation in colors.
We'll try the prompt, a man standing on
his driveway clearing snow with a
flamethrower. And we'll turn on draft
mode so that it'll generate something a
little bit faster. We can actually see
it says analyzing the scene of a man
clearing snow on his driveway using a
flamethrower. So, it's actually thinking
through this a little bit. It generated
what seems to be like the starting
frame. Here we can see it's examining
the snowy driveway scene to enhance the
man's determined stance and the cold
cinematic atmosphere. It actually
annotated some stuff. So, see these
circles and drawing here? We've seen
that's a really good method for telling
these images what to do when they become
videos. Well, this just drew those on
there for me. I didn't have to actually
annotate anything. It's using AI to do
the annotation. It's still going. But,
you know what's crazy about it is it
made this video of this guy with the
flamethrower. But the flamethrower
looked off, like the flames weren't
coming out of the front of it. And it
seemed to have noticed that and then
remade the video fixing it so that the
flames actually come out of the front of
the flamethrower. Like that's wild. Like
this is to me like a truly agentic video
model. It checks its work and then goes
back and makes its work better. Okay, so
it's done. And it did take a few
minutes. So it was a little bit longer
than I thought, but we can see it
generated four drafts. And you can see
in this first one, the flames aren't
really coming out of the flamethrower.
They're coming out of the top. and it
doesn't really look like snow's melting
or anything. We jump to the second
draft, same kind of issues. Then we jump
to the third draft and look, now it's
actually coming out of the flamethrower.
And we're seeing the snow on the ground
melt. And then for whatever reason, the
final version is fairly jacked up where
a second guy just sort of pops in and
there's like a weird jump cut. But this
third one here is pretty good. And we
can see that's a draft. So, let's go
ahead and upscale this one into HDR and
turn it into not a draft. And now we
have our higher definition version in
720p. And if I wanted to, I could modify
it, extend it, or make more like this.
But we'll leave it there for now. So,
you could go and play around with it and
see what you get out of it. The video
model cling 2.5, which a lot of people
say is pretty dang comparable to VO3,
has been made available in various
platforms. If you use Craya AI, you can
now use Clling 2.5 directly inside of
Crea. Or if you're more of a fan of
Leonardo AI, you can generate videos
with Cling 2.5 directly inside of
Leonardo as well. Let's go ahead and do
it inside of Leonardo. Create with Cling
2.5. We'll make sure we have video
selected. And then over on model, it's
still selected as VO3. So, let's go
ahead and click that and swap it over to
Cling 2.5 Turbo. and we'll give it the
prompt, a fashion show where everyone
walking the runway is wearing clothing
made of spaghetti. I will say that Cling
2.5 is pretty slow at generating. It's
been generating for over 7 minutes now
and I still haven't gotten my video. It
took kind of forever to generate, well
over 15 minutes, but this was the output
that we got from Cling 2.5. I mean,
yeah, it looks like spaghetti noodles on
those models. It followed the prompt. I
don't know if I just saw this video if I
would realize that's supposed to be
spaghetti. It just kind of more looks
like strings. But this is cling 2.5. For
the sake of comparison, this is what V3
created given the exact same prompt.
Something that in my opinion is much
more clearly looking like spaghetti. And
that tie is kind of awesome. The
platform Higsfield AI also added Clling
2.5. So if you want another platform to
go use it in, it's there as well. But
they also added Juan 2.5 which is pretty
widely regarded as the best open-source
AI video model. So it's open source. You
have a strong enough computer. You can
actually run this one locally and it
generates sound and is pretty comparable
to VO3. But let's give one 2.5 a try
inside of Higsfield. So I'll come up to
the top or video. We'll select one 2.5
here. And since this one generates audio
as well, let's give it a prompt. a
traffic jam where every car is shaped
like a rubber duck and when the driver
honks the horns it sounds like a squeaky
toy. And I'm just going to generate it
at 480p just to kind of speed up the
process, but you can generate all the
way up to 1080p and you can generate 5
or 10 seconds, but I'm just trying to
make a quick demo. So, let's go ahead
and generate this. And it does say that
a start frame is required. So, let's go
ahead and take this exact prompt and
we'll generate our starting image. Paste
that in here. Traffic jam where every
car is blah blah blah. So, let's go
ahead and use the model. They have less
models available than I thought. Um, so
let's go ahead and use the flux context
max model to generate this image. And we
got a couple options for our traffic
jam. So, let's go ahead and use this
one. We'll click it on video. And then
once again, we'll leave it on one 2.5.
And we still have our prompt in here.
So, let's go ahead and now generate it
with our squeaky toy image. And this is
what we got out of it.
[Music]
I mean, it doesn't really sound like a
duck squeaking, and I don't know why
they randomly get like horns in their
mouth that like disappear, but it is
another model that will generate both
video and audio for you. I just picked a
very, very random example to try. So,
yeah, that's available over on Higsfield
as of right now. And just as a quick
update in case you're curious, if you
have a Crea account, I did notice that
Juan 2.5 is available inside of Crea now
as well. So, multiple platforms with
multiple video tools all sort of
available. My personal choice has been
Leonardo, but I'm definitely biased. And
Crea and Higsfield have a lot of great
models that you can use inside of them
as well. The tricky part with AI right
now isn't finding cool tools. It's
getting them to actually work together.
You use a chatbot for one thing, then
copy and paste it into another tool for
the next step, then hop into another
platform for images. Everything feels so
scattered with no easy way to connect
the dots. And that's where Make comes
in. It basically gives you one place to
build and run entire systems of AI
agents and automations all in real time.
Let me give you an example of what that
looks like. I set up a workflow that I
call the campaign in a box agent.
Picture you're a marketing agency that
just picked up a new client, say a copy
brand. Normally, you'd have a team doing
research, writing copy, designing ads,
and scheduling posts. With Make, you can
have AI agents handle all of that on one
visual platform. Here's the flow. First,
an AI research agent scan social media
to figure out what people are saying
about coffee right now. That feeds into
a copywriting agent that drafts ad copy
and captions in the client's voice. At
the same time, a design agent spins up
creative concepts, product shots,
carousel ads, even mock-ups with new
slogans. Once it's ready, the post gets
pushed straight into auler like Meta Ads
Manager or Buffer. And finally, the
whole system loops back with analytics
inside Make Grid, so you can see which
ads are working in real time and even
shift more budget to the top performing
content automatically. This isn't just
automation, it's orchestration. Instead
of juggling disconnected tools, you've
got a living campaign that can adapt,
scale, and self-optimize all from a
single dashboard. For agencies, this
means less time stuck in production
bottlenecks and more time focusing on
strategy and clients. And for
businesses, it means faster workflows,
lower costs, and better results. So, if
you've been wondering how to actually
put AI to work in your business, this is
the way. Make lets you build, scale, and
control AIdriven workflows at every
level. And right now, they're giving my
audience one month free of the pro plan
if you use the link below. So whether
you're running an agency or a fintech
startup or just want to automate
smarter, now's the time to try it. Hit
the link in the description, grab your
free month, and start orchestrating your
AI powered business with Make. Thanks so
much to make.com for sponsoring this
one. Now, let's get back to the rest of
the video. Now that we've talked about
generating video, let's talk about
editing video. There's this platform
called Mirage, and they used to be
called Captions, but they rebranded as
Mirage recently, and it's an AI video
editing tool. Now, it also makes like AI
avatars, but their newest feature is the
ability to make edits entirely with
text. Want to zoom at 3 seconds? Just
type that into the box. Need captions
added? Done in a snap. You can even type
a vibe you're going for, and our AI
editing tool will apply the right style
and aesthetic to bring it to life. Now,
this editing feature that they just
rolled out is on the mobile app. So,
even if I logged into Mirage Studio on
my desktop, we won't see this editing
feature. So, let's pop it open on the
phone here. So, this is what the app
looks like when you're inside of it. I
do not have a paid plan. You can see it
is prompting me to get the paid plan up
in the top right. But, let's say I want
to import some videos and have it edit
these videos together. There is one
thing that I find slightly annoying
about this product, but it's not that
big of a deal. But if I press the import
button and let's say I pull in a couple
videos from my recent trip to New York.
Like here's one from the plane right
here. Here's one from inside of a taxi.
Here's another from inside of a taxi
right here. So I'm going to select these
three and let's import three items. And
it brings me to this page here. And you
can see there's this slider for manual
edit and AI edit. If I try to click on
AIE, I get this error at the top. AIEdit
not submitted. Video must be in 916. A
why? Why can't I just do this with 16:9
videos also? But B, if it only works
with 916 aspect ratio videos, why let me
select them on this page? Why not just
gray out the ones that aren't usable and
make the ones that aren't usable
something that I can select just so I
don't get partway through the process
and then find out I can't actually do
what I want. But because of that
constraint, I really quickly recorded
two vertical videos of me in my office.
One is this like selfie angle shot here
and another is what my camera sees which
you can see in this video here. So I'll
go ahead and trim both of these. Select
those videos. Import two items. And now
let's switch to AIEdit. And well when I
try to switch to AI edit it says project
must only have one clip. So why did you
let me select two clips? Okay. I guess
you could manually edit these and that's
why it lets you select it. But it's just
I find this kind of annoying. Like I
want to know what I can't do before I
get to the point where it tells me I
can't do it. Anyway, I'm being very kind
of nitpicky here. So, let's just
unselect this one and we'll pick this
11se second video. Import one item. And
now I can select AIEit. Yay. All right.
So, we've got some edit styles here.
Parallel play isn't just for kids. It
works for adults, too.
Plant care isn't just about keeping them
alive. It's about learning how to
listen.
I'll select this one down here. I have
no idea how it's going to work because
there's no speaking in my video. It's
just purely a video with no audio. So,
it may have no idea how to edit this.
But, let's go ahead and select that one
and let's generate the edit. Let's just
see what it does if I give it a quick 11
second clip and a style. So, yeah, it
didn't know how to do that either. It
says AIET not supported. No speakers or
no words detected. All right. So, I
guess I have to make a video with me
actually talking because it can't edit
unless they're speaking. All stuff I
wish I knew before sort of getting down
the road of the process. All right, so I
just got done recording a vertical video
on my phone here and let's see if I can
finally get this AI edit to do something
for us. Import one item. AI edit style
neon generate edit progress. Progress.
All right, so now it's done and it
opened it in this editor and I can hear
myself but I can't see the edited video.
Hey, Matt Wolf here. Don't forget to
subscribe to me on YouTube. There's got
to be some way to see the video here,
right? Download. No, it won't let me
download without paying. All right, so I
finally got it to work. But if I'm
trying to record my phone screen to show
it to you working, the app makes the
video black and doesn't let me share it.
So, I can't even share this outcome with
you other than doing something like
this. Hey, Matt here. Don't forget to
subscribe to me on YouTube. Like this
video, do all the things, leave me a
comment, and if you haven't already,
check out Future Tools. There's lots of
cool tools there. So, yeah, pretty
annoying that the app won't let me
actually share what it generates. And
then if I do try to export the video to
send you what that video looks like,
they want to charge me. So, I can't even
like demo this without paying, which is
unfortunate. But, we'll go ahead and
move along. We got a new update in the
Photoshop beta this week. All of those
people, myself included, who said,
"Man, Nano Banana might sort of hurt
Photoshop." Well,
Photoshop's just embracing it and
saying, "Look, you could use Nano Banana
inside of Photoshop." Now, now, if you
do have an Adobe Creative Cloud account,
open Creative Cloud, go to apps, click
on beta, and then make sure you're using
Photoshop Beta. This is where the new
features that they roll out go. They go
into the beta version. And make sure you
have the most up-to-date version. I need
to update my Photoshop beta right now to
make sure I get Nano Banana in it. Once
it's updated, go and open Photoshop. But
again, make sure that you're opening the
Photoshop beta. I actually have both
installed. We want to be using beta
because that's what's got nano banana.
So, I opened this image in Photoshop.
You can use this handy select subject
feature. If I select this and then just
click on the guy, it actually finds the
outline of just this guy and ignores
everything else. And then I can click on
generative fill here. And then over
here, there's a button that says choose
model. If I click on that, you can see
we have options for Firefly Image 3, Lux
Context Pro, and Nano Banana. So, let's
go ahead and select Nano Banana. And
then for our prompt, let's say turn him
into a green alien holding a futuristic
bow. And then we'll generate that.
Actually, just realized the moon was
selected as well, but it did a perfect
job of what I asked for. And the nice
thing is it did these changes on a new
layer. So, if I hide this layer, you
could see the old layer right underneath
it. So I could continue to like screw
with other elements and it's
nondestructive. So pretty cool feature
to have in Photoshop. Now Halo AI rolled
out some sort of new agent. They say
introducing Halo AI agent, your nextgen
creative flow free for one week. Just
talk and watch your ideas come alive on
the infinite canvas. The agent selects
the best models, plans the workflow, and
brings your vision to life. Images,
videos, audio, all in one place. So if I
jump on over to haloai.video/agent,
video/ agent. This is where you can play
around with it. And we can see over here
it does say multimodal creation is
coming. So images, videos, and audio all
created with one agent. Isn't actually a
feature that's fully rolled out yet, I
guess. But we can see here if I click on
model, they've got the Halo O2 video
model. And then under image model,
they've got Nano Banana, Cadream 4.0,
Flux Context, Quinn, and Colors. And up
here you can see you can either select
your model or leave it on auto and it
will decide the best model to pick for
you. And if I had to guess, this is the
way most UIs are going to go. So when
you use those tools like Leonardo or
Crea or Higsfield or whatever and you
tell it what you want out of it, I
imagine in the future they'll all have
an auto selector that will pick the best
model based on your prompt. But let's go
ahead and say create a mood board
focused on wolves and the color purple.
It says you've done enough. Now it's my
turn. Thank you. All right. Smart plan.
Create a mood board centered around
wolves and the color purple. So it's
searching for images featuring wolves
and the color purple. Oh, look at this.
Okay. Okay. So these are image searches.
These aren't AI generated. You can see
image searched. While this is working, I
can actually click in an image, click on
full screen, and see this image bigger.
Now, this does say Miniax Halo AI. So,
did it generate this or did it find it?
Okay, that's interesting. This one has a
dreams time watermark on it, which is a
stock photo website. And then Miniax and
Halo AI put their own watermark over an
already watermarked image. So, these are
images that it found online. It's just
putting its own watermark on images that
it doesn't own. Now it says calling
image generation tool to create four
images with the same prompt for the mood
board. So it's actually now generating
images and it doesn't seem to be doing a
good job at it. We can see here uh
calling the image generation tool to
create four images with the same prompt
for the mood board and it says image
generation completed. I don't know which
one it generated but then down here
generating more with an unknown error.
And now it's trying to generate again,
but we can see a couple times in a row
it says image generation unknown error.
Though it seemed to be able to find some
images, just it struggles to generate
new images. Here's another one that says
Adobe Stock on it on one side and then
Miniax Halo on the other. Got to love
just like watermarking images that are
owned by other people. All right, so it
finally created some other images here
based on the mood board. This one even
still has a dreams time watermark right
in the middle of it. made some sort of
like montage collage looking image and
some images of like closeup on like
purple fur. All right, then if I select
multiple and then try to rightclick it
just only selects one. But I could move
them around on the board together.
Pretty interesting. I don't know the
exact like best use case for this yet. I
guess if you're just trying to build out
like a giant mood board and you want all
of the images on the mood board to
either be searched or generated, then
there you go. Not something I personally
see myself using, but I'm sure there's
people watching this going, "I know
exactly how I'll use that.
I just don't know how I would." And
since we're talking about boards and
mood boards and vision boards and stuff,
there's a new tool from Google called
Mixboard. Kind of the same idea as what
we were just looking at actually, and it
is in public beta in the US right now.
So, if you're outside of the US, I don't
believe you have access to this. But if
we go to labs.google/mixboard,
you get a page like this. And if we look
into one of their examples here, you
could see they made a board of birds
with googly eyes. One thing I find
annoying is I can't like click and move
around. A lot of times you can like
right click and sort of scroll around
the screen, but that doesn't work. I
actually have to use like the scroll
wheels to move around. So once you have
a bunch of images in a mood board like
this or in a mix board like this, one
thing you can do is sort of start to
blend them together. So let's say I want
to take this like peacock here and this
red bird here, put them side by side and
select both of them. You can see it
pulled these images down into my prompt
box and say blend these two images. And
then pretty quickly down here we can see
it's generating another image. And
here's our two images blended. I can
obviously upload my own images.
Theoretically I should be able to
generate new images. And it all goes
onto this like mood board mixboard thing
in Google. Very similar to what we were
just looking at but less of the like
agentic features and more of like a
design board to drop images on. and uh
then combine images in interesting ways.
If you're a fan of Notebook LM like I
am, they rolled out some new features
this week. Flashcards and quizzes are
officially 100% rolled out to all users
in all markets. So, Notebook LM is a
platform where you can upload a bunch
of, you know, PDFs and websites and a
ton of information and then you can
create audio overviews, video overviews,
mind maps, reports, and then also ask
questions about those documents. We've
covered Notebook LM a lot in past
videos. The two new features are
flashcards and quizzes. You can create a
flash card on whatever content is loaded
in here and you can create quizzes since
we've been on this birds aren't real
train lately. Let's see what kind of
flash cards it makes for us. We can see
here the first flash card, what is the
birds aren't real movement? And then
flip it over, a satirical conspiracy
theory movement which posits that birds
are actually drones operated by the US
government. Satirical, I don't know
about that. who is credited with
creating the birds aren't real
conspiracy theory that dude. So you
could see for like school and education
purposes if you were to load a bunch of
like educational information in here you
could quiz yourself with flashcards as
well as an actual quiz. So here's what a
quiz might look like. According to the
source material, what was the original
catalyst for Peter McKenzo's creating
the birds aren't real movement? Uh this
one 2017 Women's March where he
improvised the theory as a joke among
counterprotesters. So we can just go
through and quiz oursel on all the
information. So let's imagine you're a
college student and you just took in a
bunch of lectures. Well, let's say you
did an audio recording of the lecture.
We'll take that audio recording, put it
into Notebook LM or get it transcribed,
put the transcription in Notebook LM,
have it create quizzes and flashcards
for you, and you've got a really good
educational resource. Since we're
talking about Google, they're also
rolling out new AI features directly in
Chrome. From what I understand, you have
to be on one of Google's paid plans. I
can't confirm that 100%, but it does say
starting today, we're rolling out a
Gemini in Chrome to Mac and Windows
desktop users in the US. Okay, so maybe
it is available to everybody. And it
does say it'll be available to
businesses in the coming weeks. So, this
current browser that I'm in is an actual
business account. So, there's no Gemini
available here. You don't see it in the
browser. However, if I switch over to
the browser where I'm logged in with a
personal account and not a business
account, you can see up at the top, I've
got a little Gemini logo now in the very
top right corner. I can also essentially
get Gemini to fire up by clicking into
our chat bar. And you can see there's a
button that says, "Ask Google about this
page or highlight key points or describe
the AI startup's impact." These are all
questions that are being generated by AI
based on the content that I'm looking at
on the website. Or I can click the
Gemini button up in the top. What is
this article about?
This article discusses how Steph Curry's
venture capital firm Penny Jar Capital
invested in Burnt, an AI startup focused
on improving
Wait a second. Wait a second. Who is
Steph Curry?
Steph Curry is one of the greatest
basketball players of all time. He plays
for the Golden State Warriors and is
known for his incredible shooting
skills.
Okay. Okay. Okay. So what does he have
to do with AI then?
Gotcha. So Steph Curry's not directly
involved in the AI tech itself. His
venture capital firm, Penny Jar Capital,
invests in promising startups.
All right, you get the idea. You can
fire up the Gemini button and it will
basically read articles for you and let
you have discussions. You don't have to
do it in voice mode. If I click up here,
I could switch it to like a normal
keyboard mode as well instead of the
voice mode. And you can see that it's
sharing the article that I'm on. and you
have the option to switch between the
2.5 Pro model and the 2.5 flash model.
Now, I am on the Gemini Ultra plan,
which is their ultra expensive plan. Uh,
so I don't know if everybody has 2.5 Pro
or not. That might just be on the Ultra
plan. I can't actually confirm that, but
that would be my guess. The Pro is maybe
only on the paid plans. I don't know. It
does kind of seem like Google is going
after Perplexity Comet a little bit and
uh you know the browser company which
makes these sort of like AI agentic
browsers. I think it's only a matter of
time before this Gemini button you press
it and you tell it to do things and it
will go and browse on your behalf and
click around and copy and paste things
and do some of those like browser
operation things that we've seen tools
like chat GPT and Claude and Manis and
some of these other tools start to do.
probably going to be rolled out into
Chrome pretty soon. And I mentioned
Perplexity, so I might as well mention
this as well. They now have an email
assistant with Perplexity. And this is
one that I had planned on demoing.
However, when I started to look at it, I
realized I needed a ultra plan. And
well, the ultra plan is Perplexity's
$200 a month plan. And I'm on enough
$200 a month plans already between
Google, Claude, and Gemini. So yeah, I I
I can't I can't pull the trigger on
perplexity just for an email assistant.
But as we can see here, it will
automatically like organize your emails
into like to respond or notification or
an FYI or a meeting update. So it
automatically tags so at a glance you
can quickly see what stuff's probably
important and what's not. It's got an AI
composer to automatically help you write
emails to people. It can actually see
your calendar and help assist with
scheduling. So it says, "Sure, looping
in my assistant to find a time." The
assistant checks the calendar and
suggests times. So you can have the
assistant help with sort of booking
calls and things like that. And you can
get like summaries of like daily
meetings and emails and things you need
to take care of every day if you want.
It looks like a pretty cool email helper
tool, but sorry, I can't justify it at
the $200 a month plan. Once it's
available for the like smaller $20 a
month plan, I'll probably play with
this. But yeah, looks cool. Too rich for
my blood at this point. So far, we've
covered a ton of new tools, but I
haven't put out a news video in 2 weeks.
So, there's still a lot of stuff I want
to tell you about. So, let's jump into a
rapid fire.
[Music]
So, the week before last was Meta
Connect, and unfortunately, I didn't
make it out to MetaConnect this year,
but they did have some pretty cool
announcements. Probably the most notable
being the new Meta Ray-B band display
glasses. Now, these are just like the
Rayban Metas that everybody is used to
that have the little cameras and the
little speakers and the the stem of the
glasses and they also have built-in AI
so you can talk to, you know, Meta's
Llama AI. However, these new versions,
well, you can probably tell by the name,
have a display in them. So, when you put
them on, there's a little screen on just
one of the lenses. It's not in both
eyes, it's just in one. And it shows in
color. It's got like basically no light
bleed, so nobody around you can even
tell there's something going on on the
screen. And then the other really unique
feature about these glasses is that they
come with this wristband that they call
the neural wristband, I believe. And
this wristband can actually essentially
tell what you're trying to do. So, you
swipe around inside of the apps on your
glasses with like finger gestures. And
if you want to turn the volume up or
down, you literally kind of act like
you're turning a knob. And it's just got
some really interesting hand gestures to
control the glasses. I haven't actually
tested these myself yet. I've not
experienced this neural wristband and
how it works. But one thing that I find
very interesting is I saw Google make
very very similar glasses. And I demoed
them almost a year ago now. And yet
somehow Meta's glasses came out before
Google's glasses. And Google's were the
same thing. It was one eye. You can
actually see color and see images and
things like that in the one eye. And the
demo worked great a year ago. So just I
don't know. Weird to me that Meta was
the first to release these. But you can
see text messages directly inside of
your glasses. Although I believe it's
just WhatsApp messages, so not like
actual text messages yet. You pinch your
fingers to take a photo when you ask a
question of AI. You can actually see the
prompt that was given and then a visual
display of the response. But probably
one of the coolest features is the
ability to translate and have a
conversation with somebody that speaks a
different language. And essentially
while you're talking to them, you would
see little subtitles like right by their
face. So everything they're saying is
automatically getting translated back
into English to you so you can see it.
They're also rolling out a feature in
both these and the normal Ray-B bands
that's like a focus mode. So, when I'm
talking to somebody, if I have these
glasses on and I'm looking at them,
it'll try to isolate just the
conversation you're having and sort of
help you tune out all the rest of the
conversations around you, which seems
like a pretty cool use case as well,
especially if you're at like networking
events or parties where you're really
trying to concentrate on one person
speaking. I'm super excited to get my
hands on these, test this neural
wristband, and probably even do a
giveaway on this channel for a pair of
these Ray-B band displays. So, if you're
watching this and you're not subscribed
to this channel and you're not
subscribed to the newsletter, make sure
you do that because I do like to do
giveaways from time to time when new
cool gadgets come out. Now, this is just
scratching the surface of what these
glasses can do. Those are the main sort
of standout features, but we'll put them
through the test and play around with
them more once I can actually get my
hands on them in a couple weeks here.
Meta also showed off some cool stuff
around the metaverse. So, there's a new
feature in the Meta Quest where you can
put the headset on, walk around the
room, and it will actually map out that
room, and then after it's mapped out
that room, that becomes a digital space
that you can explore later, even if
you're not in that room later. That
seemed pretty cool. But what I thought
was even cooler was their new Horizon
Studio. This Horizon Studio, you can
actually prompt any world into
existence. You can see they gave it the
prompt ancient ruins and it created this
scene, this environment here that they
are then able to move around in. Add
treasure and trinkets. They give it that
prompt and it adds a bunch of stuff. Add
mythical guardians. It added the
guardians. So really, really cool that
you could just constantly prompt new
things into existence into this like AI
world. It's like kind of holidayy. Now,
the reason I couldn't make it to Meta
Connect this year was cuz I was in New
York at the Made on YouTube event, which
is an annual event where YouTube
announces all of the new things that
they're rolling out. And this year, it
was a lot of AI stuff. As a YouTuber,
I'm really excited about this Ask
Studio. If you're not a YouTuber, you
probably don't care. But basically, it's
an AI bot that lives in the backend
studio of your YouTube channel where you
can ask questions about your analytics
and get suggestions on future videos and
things like that. It's just an AI bot
that understands your data and your
stats and your channel that you can chat
with. They're rolling out AB testing to
test titles. You've already been able to
do it with thumbnails. Now you can do it
with titles. Not AI related, but pretty
cool if you're a YouTuber. So, YouTube
has been doing autodubbing for a little
while now on some channels. My channel
has had it where I speak all of my
videos in English, but if you're in
India and you watch one of my videos, it
will automatically try to translate it
for you by default. If you're in Mexico
and you try to watch it down there, it
will automatically try to translate it
to Spanish. But it doesn't look like I'm
speaking. It just looks like it was
dubbed over with another voice. Well,
now YouTube is rolling out autodubbing
with lipsync. So, it will actually in
the future look like me and my lips
moving and speaking the language that
you're hearing with my voice. That's
going to be wild. Now, this isn't fully
rolled out yet, but this is going to be
really, really cool. They're also
rolling out a likeness detection
because, well, AI deep fakes are getting
easier and easier, and pretty much
anybody can do them now. And well, if
you don't want your likeness being used
on YouTube, even if it wasn't really
you, well, they're building technology
to better detect that and stop people
from stealing your likeness and like
deep faking you into videos. A few of
the other random AI features they're
rolling out, you can turn everyday
videos into catchy soundtracks. So, if
you hear like a funny phrase, a
memorable quote, or a one-of-a-kind
sound, they have a speechto song
remixing tool that uses LIA 2, which is
DeepMind's most advanced AI music model,
and it will convert whatever sort of
sound bites or quotes or whatever you
give it into a music video that sounds
something like this.
Isn't it almost cuffing season? I know
you're looking for that new date spot.
Isn't it almost cuffing season?
Isn't it almost cuffing season? Isn't it
almost?
So, you know, a new random meme
generator. And as we predicted and
talked about in previous videos, they
are rolling V3 directly into YouTube
shorts. So, you can see they've
partnered with DeepMind to bring a
custom version of V3 to YouTube and
they're allowing users of the platform
to use it for free directly in shorts.
And right now, it's rolling out in the
US, UK, Canada, Australia, and New
Zealand. and plans for more countries
after that. I'm not a huge fan of this
feature. I think most of the stuff I
made on YouTube I was really excited
about and pumped up to try out in the
future. This is one of the things that
they announced that I went, I don't know
if that's going to be good. Isn't that
just going to make it so our shorts feed
is all sort of AI generated slop? I
don't know if you make it that easy for
anybody to just press a button, generate
AI slop, and push it to the feed. I
don't know. That seems like we might get
flooded with that. We'll see. We'll see.
Overall, I was a huge fan of the made on
YouTube event and most of the
announcements they made, but yeah, the
VO3 and shorts, not something I'm super
excited about. And along the same lines
of AI slop, apparently being an AI
musician can land you a record deal.
Oh, somebody kill me, please. So, this
AI artist named Za Zen Monaet climbs the
charts and signs a multi-million dollar
record deal. So, this is somebody who
actually uses Sununo to turn their own
lyrics, so they write their lyrics
themselves, I'm guessing, into music.
And the label offered them $3 million to
sign this artist. And since we're
speaking about leveraging AI to make
money, I thought this would be fun to
talk about. So, there's an app called
Neon, and you can find it in the App
Store. I believe of both Apple and
Android. And it's an app that will pay
you to share your phone calls. So
basically, here's how it works. So let's
say I'm calling my mom and I call her
through this app. It will record those
conversations and send that conversation
into some sort of data center to train
on that conversation. And the person who
made the call makes about 30 cents per
minute and can max out at about $30 a
day by doing this. It doesn't record
your calls if you're just using the
normal phone app. You do have to use
this specific app and you have to have
consent from the person on the other
side and they have to be using the same
app as well. If you call somebody with
this app and they're not using the app
and they haven't given consent, it's
only going to record your side of the
conversation. If you're both using the
app and you both gave consent, it will
record both sides of the conversation.
And again, all of that conversation goes
in as training data that this data
company can then sell to the AI model
creators. And you earn money by
basically allowing this app to spy on
your calls and use it for training data.
And you might say, well, who would do
that? Who would want to use an app that
records and sends all of their
conversation data to like big tech
companies? Well, as of this recording,
it's the number seventh most downloaded
app for iPhone. If you're on an Android
phone, well, you now have Nano Banana
Editing directly inside of Google
Photos. If you're a fan of Adobe's
Firefly boards, well, they just rolled
out two new AI video models into their
platform. You can now use Runway Alif
and Moon Valley's Mary or Marray
directly inside of the boards app. 11
Labs rolled out an update this week
called Studio 3.0. They claim it's their
most advanced AI audio model, and it now
has video support. I haven't really put
this one to the test yet, but I
guarantee we'll be using 11 Labs quite a
bit in some future videos. Also, this is
pretty cool. Automatic captioning,
speech correction for real life
recordings, and multiplayer commenting.
So, it looks like you can
collaboratively edit stuff in 11 Labs
with other users. If you like generating
music, Sunno just rolled out V5, which
is their new state-of-the-art music
generation model. I went and tried to
generate some new songs with V5 and
compared them to version 4.5, and
honestly had a pretty hard time telling
the difference, but we will put through
its motions. We've got some big ideas of
ways we want to test in some future
videos, so make sure you're subscribed
if you want to see that. And since we're
talking about Sununo, they also launched
their own DAW, which stands for digital
audio workstation. It's basically your
audio editor. So, there's a brand new
like audio timeline editor directly
inside of Sunno. Again, something we
will be playing with a little bit more
later, but it sounds like you can
generate songs and then get really,
really granular with the editing of
those songs. So, that sounds pretty
cool. Now, over the last couple weeks,
there was a handful of news in the large
language model world. I've sort of
backed off on trying to explain the
benefits and the differences of these
new models because quite honestly, it
all feels so marginal to me and to the
majority of the world. The improvements
in these LLMs doesn't really make a
difference unless you're, you know, a
developer or somebody that's really,
really, really putting these models to
their limits. But here's what we got
over the last couple weeks. So, we got a
couple new models out of Google. Gemini
2.5 Flash and Flash Light. Now, these
are models that have been available, but
they made some improvements in the
quality and speed to them so that
they're a little bit more performant.
XAI rolled out Gro 4 Fast, which is a
faster but probably slightly dumber Gro
model, but actually performs pretty dang
close to Gro 4 in almost all of these
benchmarks they tested it on. We got a
couple new models out of Alibaba. We got
Quinn3 Max, which you can actually play
with for free over at chat.quinn.ai.
Apparently, this one's really good at
coding and agentic skills. We can see
the red bars here as it's compared to
Quinn 3, big long number. Edclaude Opus
4 and Deepseek V3.1. And it pretty much
beats all of those in all of them except
for the Sweetbench here. Basically
showing that it's pretty good at code.
We also got Quinn 3 Omni out of Alibaba.
So this is an Omni model that can manage
text, image, audio, and video all in one
model. And they apparently open source
this one as well. OpenAI is trying to
build in some age checks into the
system. And it sounds like it's going to
try to predict their age based on the
conversations they're having, not by
some sort of like age verification form
or something. It says down here, even
the most advanced systems will sometimes
struggle to predict age. If we're not
confident about someone's age or have
incomplete information, we'll take the
safer route and default to the under 18
experience. So, if you talk like
somebody that's under 18, it might guess
that you're under 18 and give you the
kid-friendly chat GPT. But, they did
also add parental controls where parents
can actively take control over what kids
see when they're using chat GPT. And
since we're talking about OpenAI and
chat GPT, there is some other features
that rolled out. You can now share your
projects with other team members. I
guess the various connectors that are
available are slightly better. Like they
pull in more details via the API, and
they've made some new compliance and
security updates. So, you know, not
major updates, but if you are working
with a team, having shared projects
sounds pretty handy. The company Factory
AI this week reached number one on
Terminal Bench, which is the most
challenging general software development
benchmark. So, it actually outperformed
tools like Claude Code and Codeex CLI
from OpenAI. And they even made it so
that you can use the factory AI platform
with any interface. So, you can use it
directly inside of like VS Code or
Windsurf or Cursor or whatever IDE
you're using or from places like Slack.
Anyway, this is one that I just wanted
to share because I'm an investor in
factory and I'm excited about this news.
They're making some pretty good
progress. I thought this story was
really interesting. Microsoft 365
Copilot just added enthropic models to
it. So now if you're in something like
Excel, you can actually choose whether
you want to use one of the GPT models or
one of the enthropic models.
What's going on in there?
What? And the reason this is interesting
is because well Microsoft owns 49% of
OpenAI's not forprofit side of their
company. And with Microsoft owning such
a big chunk of Open AI, you would think
they would be all in on OpenAI, but
nope. Microsoft is really diversifying
and even allowing you to use competitors
like Anthropic inside of their
platforms. And finally, you will soon be
able to attend Zoom meetings as an AI
avatar. So yeah, you'll be able to
upload an AI avatar of yourself, not be
on camera, and let your AI avatar do the
speaking for you if you don't feel like
putting clothes on or something.
I'm here live. That's not I'm not a cat.
And that's what I got for you today. I
know it was a lot. This was a fire hose
episode. And well, it's because I
skipped a couple of weeks. And quite
honestly, that's probably going to
happen a little bit more often as well.
We've got some really, really, really
big ideas for videos that really put
these tools into action. And so, you'll
probably see some different kinds of
videos starting to roll out on this
channel where we really, really figure
out the limits of some of these
software. We put them to the test. We
put them out there into real world use
cases and we try to find new,
interesting, useful ways to use a lot of
these AI tools. And it's a new style of
video we're testing. And as we work to
produce more and more of those videos,
well, the news videos may be further in
between, but I promise I will still keep
you looped in on all of the biggest,
most important news in the AI world that
you're going to want to know and
probably cut out maybe some of the fluff
that might have made it into some of
these news videos. So, stick around. If
you're interested in learning real
practical use cases for AI tools and
learning how you can actually implement
them in your business or your real life,
we've got exciting stuff coming up. So,
you're going to want to stick around for
that. Make sure you like this video, you
subscribe to this channel. That'll make
sure more videos like this show up in
your YouTube feed. Thank you so much for
tuning in and nerding out with me about
all of the latest stuff that came out in
AI over the last two weeks. Hopefully
you feel more looped in and uh that's my
goal here is to keep you looped in and
learning how to use this stuff. So,
thanks again for hanging out. Really,
really appreciate you. Hopefully, I'll
see you in the next one. Bye-bye. Thank
you so much for nerding out with me
today. If you like videos like this,
make sure to give it a thumbs up and
subscribe to this channel. I'll make
sure more videos like this show up in
your YouTube feed. And if you haven't
already, check out futuretools.io where
I share all the coolest AI tools and all
the latest AI news. And there's an
awesome free newsletter. Thanks again.
Really appreciate you. See you in the
next one.